Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- FOURTH INTERNATIONAL FILE, 1930-1980
  - Great Britain
    - Fourth International issuances, British
      - Workers Socialist League. Internal bulletins, other internal documents, and articles, 1975-1978. Includes writing by Adam Westoby (Folder 8)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-British. Memoranda, declarations, reports, articles, and miscellany
      - 1966-1971. Includes writings by Fernand Charlier, Pierre Frank, and Barry Sheppard (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - 1972-1976. Includes Report of the Fact-Finding Commission of the United Secretariat on the Internal Situation within the International Marxist Group, British Section of the Fourth International (Folder 2)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Pamphlets, articles, reports, and clippings, 1944-1976. Includes critiques of Trotskyism by the Communist Party of Great Britain (Folder 3)
    - Socialist Labour League/Workers Revolutionary Party subject file (material from various sources relating to the organization)
      - General. Pamphlets, articles, clippings, memoranda, statements, and leaflets
        - 1959-1968. Includes articles by Peter Cadogan and Walter Kendall; and pamphlet by Tony Polan, The SLL: An Autopsy (Folder 4)
        - 1970-1977. Includes statements by Robin Blick and Mark Jenkins; memorandum by Pierre Frank; and pamphlet by Tony Whelan, The Credibility Gap: The Politics of the S.L.L. (Folder 5)
      - Accusation campaign (material relating to allegations made by the Workers Revolutionary Party concerning the assassination of Leon Trotsky, and charging complicity on the part of Joseph Hansen). See also Great Britain/ Correspondence/ 1975-1979
        - Workers Revolutionary Party issuances. Pamphlets, serial issues, and leaflets. Includes some issuances of the Workers League (U.S.) See also OVERSIZE FILE
          - 1975. Includes pamphlet Security and the Fourth International: An Inquiry into the Assassination of Leon Trotsky (Folder 6)
          - 1976-1977 (Folder 7)
        - Non-Workers Revolutionary Party issuances. Bulletins, articles, statements, leaflets, reports, and clippings
          - 1975-1976. Includes articles by Sam Gordon and Charles van Gelderen; statement by Charles Curtiss; and bulletin Healy's Big Lie: The Slander Campaign against Joseph Hansen, George Novack, and the Fourth International (Folder 8)
          - 1977-1980. Includes statement by Harry Wicks (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Redgrave, Vanessa, Party membership of. Clippings and printed articles, 1974-1979 (Folder 2)
    - Writings
      - Archer, John and Mary, 1976 (Folder 3)
      - Coates, Ken
        - 1965-1967 (Folder 4)
        - 1968-1976 (Folder 5)
      - Gordon, Sam, 1964-1977 (Folder 6)
      - Healy, Gerry, 1959 (Folder 7)
      - Jenkins, Mark, 1975 (Folder 8)
      - Kemp, Tom, 1959 (Folder 9)
      - Tate, Ernest, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - Greece. Correspondence, declarations, statements, and other internal documents, 1965-1977. Includes letters by Mary-Alice Waters and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 11)
  - Guatemala. Letter, declaration, articles, and clippings, 1953-1970. Includes letter by Cedric Belfrage (Folder 12)
  - Hong Kong. Letter, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Hungary. Resolutions, pamphlet, and article, 1956-1966. Includes writings by Gerry Healy and Ernest Mandel (Folder 14)
  - Iceland. Letter, 1972 (Folder 15)
  - India
    - General. Statements, memoranda, other internal documents, and articles, 1960-1976. Includes writings by Sharad Jhaveri (Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1976. Includes letters by R. N. Arya, Sailen Banerji, Jack Barnes, Upali Cooray, Magan Desai, Ross Dowson, Gus Horowitz, Sharad Jhaveri, S. B. Kolpe, Caroline Lund, Ernest and Gisela Mandel, Pankaj Roy, and Ed Shaw (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Indonesia. Correspondence, memoranda, resolution, and clipping, 1945-1966. Includes letters by John Andu, Bob Chester, Attorney General Tom Clark, and Evelyn Reed (Folder 2)
  - Iran. Letter by Lawrence Trainor, and memoranda, 1966-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Ireland. Correspondence, pamphlet, leaflet, and articles, 1962-1976. Includes letters by Gerry Foley, Bob Purdie, and John Riddell, and writing by Charles van Gelderen (Folder 4)
  - Israel (including material on Palestinians). Correspondence, declaration, statement, report, and articles, 1956-1977. Includes letters by Sam Gordon and Gus Horowitz (Folder 5)
  - Italy
    - General. Reports, other internal documents, and articles, 1959-1972. Includes writings by Sirio di Giuliomaria and Livio Maitan (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1972. Includes letters by Sirio di Giuliomaria, Farrell Dobbs, Franco Grisolia, David Keil, Livio Maitan, George Novack, Peng Shu-tse, Giulio Savelli, Barry Sheppard, T. Venturi, and Libero Villone (Folder 7)
  - Jamaica. Letter by Livio Maitan, 1961 (Folder 8)
  - Japan. Correspondence, reports, serial issues, statements, leaflets, and articles, 1960-1976. Includes letters by Upali Cooray, Farrell Dobbs, Pierre Frank, T. Furusato, Gerry Healy, Kyoji Nishi, S. Okatani, Yohichi Sakai, Ed Shaw, and Eichii Yamanishi, and writing by Peng Shu-tse (Folder 9)
  - Korea. Articles by Tariq Ali and Luc Nattier, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - Lebanon. Correspondence, 1966-1973. Includes letter by Gisela Mandel (Folder 11)
  - Luxemburg. Letter, 1973 (Folder 12)
  - Mexico
    - Correspondence
      - 1938-1969. Includes letters by Manuel Aguilar, Daniel Camejo, Peter Camejo, Farrell Dobbs, Pierre Frank, Adolfo Gilly, Pilar, Diego Rivera, and Ed Shaw (Folder 13)
      - 1970-1977. Includes letters by Manuel and Mara Aguilar, Philip Ames, Farrell Dobbs, Richard Garza, Ricardo Hernandez, Gus Horowitz, Ernest Mandel, Evelyn Sell, Ed Shaw, and Barry Sheppard (Folder 14)
    - Fourth International issuances, Mexican. Internal bulletins, resolutions, speeches, conference documents, other internal documents, articles, serial issues, and leaflets
      - 1941-1965. Includes writing by Manuel Aguilar (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - 1966-1972. Includes writings by Manuel Aguilar, Daniel Camejo, Ricardo Hernandez, and Ricardo Ochoa (Folder 2)
      - 1975-1976. Includes writings by Ricardo Hernandez (Folder 3)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Mexican. Reports, resolutions, statements, and other internal documents, 1967-1976 (Folder 4)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Appeals, articles, clippings, and other writings, 1967-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Namibia. Letter by Pierre Frank, article by Franz J. T. Lee, and newsletters, 1964 (Folder 6)
  - Netherlands. Correspondence, declaration, article, and serial issue, 1945-1973. Includes letter by George Shriver, and article by Luc Nattier (Folder 7)
  - New Zealand. Correspondence, resolution, and minutes, 1965-1973. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, George Fyson, Gus Horowitz, Russell Johnson, Keith Locke, Hector MacNeill, Paul Piesse, Ed Shaw, and Barry Sheppard (Folder 8)
  - Nicaragua. Interview with Ramon Romero, and internal document by Fausto Amador, 1962-1977 (Folder 9)
  - Nigeria. Correspondence, and article, 1964-1972 (Folder 10)
  - Pakistan. Letter by Tariq Ali, and clippings, 1970-1972 (Folder 11)
  - Panama. Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Folder 12)
  - Peru
    - Blanco (Hugo) defense campaign. See also Peru/Correspondence
      - General. Press releases, memoranda, articles, appeals, leaflets, drawing of Blanco, and miscellany, 1963-1972 (Folder 13)
      - Clippings, 1963-1976 (Folder 14)
    - Correspondence
      - 1965-1970. Includes letters by Hugo Blanco, Peter Camejo, Pedro Candela Santillana, Pierre Frank, Livio Maitan, Ernest Mandel, Luc Nattier, and Charles van Gelderen (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - 1971-1976. Includes letters by Mara Aguilar, Hugo Blanco, George Breitman, Peter Camejo, Fred Halstead, Livio Maitan, Harry Ring, Ed Shaw, Mary-Alice Waters, Judy White, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 2)
    - Fourth International issuances, Peruvian. Internal bulletins, other internal documents, serial issues, pamphlets, and leaflets
      - 1945-1960 (Folder 3)
      - 1961. Includes pamphlet by Ismael Frias (Folder 4)
      - 1965-1975. Includes pamphlet by Hector Bejar (Folder 5)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Peruvian. Report, declaration, other internal documents, and articles, 1962-1974. Includes writings by Peter Camejo, Richard Garza, Livio Maitan, Humberto Valenzuela, and Luis Vitale (Folder 6)
    - Non-Fourth International issuances. Articles and circulars, 1965-1972 (Folder 7)
    - Writings by Hugo Blanco, 1968-1972 (Folder 8)
  - Philippines. Correspondence and articles, 1969-1972. Includes letters by John R. Glenn, and writings by Glenn and C. Frank Glass (Folder 9)
  - Poland. Correspondence, appeals, articles, leaflets, and pamphlets, 1966. Includes letters by Isaac Deutscher and Pierre Frank (Folder 10)
  - Portugal
    - Correspondence, 1974-1976. Includes letters by Pierre Frank, Peng Shu-tse, and Tony Thomas (Folder 11)
    - Fourth International issuances, Portuguese. Internal bulletins, resolutions, and other internal documents, 1975 (Folder 12)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Portuguese. Reports, resolutions, statements, other internal documents, pamphlet, and articles, 1975-1976. Includes writings by Pierre Frank, Sharad Jhaveri, Livio Maitan, Ernest Mandel, Nahuel Moreno, and Peng Shu-tse (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico. Letter and report by Richard Garza, 1971 (Folder 2)
  - Singapore. Letters by T. Reilly, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - South Africa. Correspondence, appeals, articles, and clippings, 1959-1978. Includes letters by C. Frank Glass, Franz J. T. Lee, Joyce Meissenheimer, L. Mqotsi, Art Sharon, and I. B. Tabata, and writings by Lee, Mqotsi, Tabata, and Anna Jack (Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union
    - General. Correspondence and printed matter, 1959-1978. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs and Pierre Frank, and printed critiques of Trotskyism by the Communist Party of the Soviet Union (Folder 5)
    - Fourth International issuances, Non-Soviet. Resolutions, declarations, articles, and pamphlets, 1946-1976. Includes writings by Tariq Ali, Bert Cochran, Pierre Frank, Ted Grant, Fred Halstead, Ted Harding, Tom Kemp, Ernest Mandel, and Michel Pablo, and pamphlet Dossier de la "Destalinisation" (Folder 6)
  - Spain
    - General. Resolutions, declaration, other internal documents, and articles, 1936-1975. Includes writings by Harry Milton and Max Sterling (Folder 7)
    - Fourth International issuances, Spanish
      - 1932-1933. Comunismo issues (Folder 8)
      - 1963-1977. Internal bulletins, declarations, other internal documents, and serial issues (Folder 9)
  - Sri Lanka
    - General. Internal documents, articles, and pamphlets, 1962-1979. Includes writings by Tamara Deutscher and Gerry Healy (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1974. Includes letters by Upali Cooray, Farrell Dobbs, Ross Dowson, Pierre Frank, Leslie Goonewardene, Gerry Healy, Gus Horowitz, Tom Kerry, Ernest Mandel, Edmund Samarakkody, Barry Sheppard, Bala Tampoe, Sydney Wanasinghe, and Mary-Alice Waters (Folder 11)
    - Fourth International issuances, Sri Lankan. Resolutions, declarations, statements, other internal documents, pamphlets, and articles, 1959-1971. Includes writings by V. Karalasingham, Edmund Samarakkody, Bala Tampoe, and Sydney Wanasinghe (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Sweden. Correspondence and manifesto, 1970-1973. Includes letters by Olga Bruce, Peter Camejo, Gerry Foley, Jan Garrett, and Tom Gustafsson (Folder 2)
  - Switzerland. Correspondence, 1959-1963. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs and George von Steiger (Folder 3)
  - Taiwan. Correspondence and resolutions, 1977-1978. Includes letter by Wang Fan-hsi (Folder 4)
  - Tanzania. Letter by Robin Blackburn, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Trinidad. Letter, resolution, and addresses, 1946 (Folder 6)
  - United States. See SOCIALIST WORKERS PARTY FILE
  - Uruguay
    - General. Correspondence and internal documents, 1967-1974. Includes letter by Peter Camejo (Folder 7)
    - Fourth International issuances, Uruguayan. Internal bulletins, other internal documents, serial issues, and leaflets, 1940-1973 (Folder 8)
  - Venezuela
    - General. Clippings, articles, and miscellany, 1962-1971 (Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1977. Includes letters by Daniel Camejo, Peter Camejo, Livio Maitan, and Alfonso Ramirez (Folder 10)
    - Fourth International issuances, Venezuelan. Internal bulletin, declarations, statements, other internal documents, articles, and leaflets, 1962-1978. Includes writings by Daniel Camejo and Alfonso Ramirez (Folder 11)
  - Vietnam. Correspondence, report, memoranda, appeals, and articles, 1966-1975. Includes letters by Fred Halstead and Peng Shu-tse, and writings by C. Frank Glass and Ernest Mandel (Folder 12)
- SOCIALIST WORKERS PARTY FILE, 1929-1979
  - Circulated internal documents. Resolutions, statements, reports, speeches, memoranda, minutes, and discussion documents
    - 1935-1936. Includes writings by Martin Abern, James P. Cannon, A. J. Muste, Hugo Oehler, Tom Stamm, Max Sterling, Jack Weber, and Joseph Zack (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - 1939-1944 (ca.) Includes excerpts from minutes of Political Committee; report of maritime trade union fraction; and writings by James Burnham and James P. Cannon (Folder 14)
    - 1945. Includes selected minutes of Political Committee; and report by Murry Weiss on anti-fascist campaign (Folder 15)
    - 1948-1951. Includes discussion documents on Henry A. Wallace movement (Folder 16)
    - 1953-1954. Includes speeches by George Clarke and Milt Zaslow; and discussion documents by Marjorie McGowan and Jeanne Morgan (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - 1957-1959. Includes report on Morton Sobell case work (Folder 2)
    - 1961-1964. Includes selected minutes of Political Committee; and writings by Farrell Dobbs (Folder 3)
  - Constitutions and declaration of principles, 1939-1977 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - 1935-1945. Includes letters by Martin Abern, James Burnham, James P. Cannon, Vincent R. Dunne, Albert Goldman, Nathan Gould, Bert Hanman, A. J. Muste, Evelyn Reed, Max Sterling, and Jack Weber (Folder 5)
    - 1946-1951. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Grace Carlson, Bob Chester, Farrell Dobbs, Vincent R. Dunne, James T. Farrell, Albert Goldman, Clara Kaye, Felix Morrow, George Novack, Morris Stein, and Milt Zaslow (Folder 6)
    - 1952-1953. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Vincent R. Dunne, Jeanne Morgan, George Novack, Ted Selander, Myra Tanner Weiss, and John G. Wright (Folder 7)
    - 1954-1961. Includes letters by George Breitman, James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Carl Feingold, Joseph Freeman, Julia Houdek, Sherry Mangan, Jeanne Morgan, George Novack, Jean Simon, Arne Swabeck, Lawrence Trainor, Tim Wohlforth, and John G. Wright (Folder 8)
    - 1962. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Carl Feingold, Milton Genecin, Julia Houdek, George Novack, Wendell Phillips, Art Sharon, and Geoffrey White (Folder 9)
    - 1963-1970. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, Peter Camejo, James P. Cannon, Farrell Dobbs, Carl Feingold, Richard Fraser, Milton Genecin, Allan and Beatrice Hansen, Tom Leonard, Frank Lovell, George Novack, Evelyn Reed, and George Weissman (Folder 10)
    - 1971-1977. Includes letters by Jack Barnes, George Breitman, Anne Chester, Milton Genecin, Barbara Gregorich, Tom Kerry, Barry Sheppard, Jessica Star, Jean van Heijenoort, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 11)
  - Election campaign material. Pamphlets, leaflets, clippings, and statistics, 1940-1970 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Freedom of Information Act requests to Central Intelligence Agency and Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1975 (Folder 2)
  - International Socialist Review file
    - General. Miscellaneous financial records, circulation statistics, and promotional material, 1956-1966 (Folder 3)
    - Artwork, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - Labor Action issues, 1936-1937 (Folder 5)
  - Miscellany. Memoranda, meeting announcements, and miscellaneous financial records, 1955-1972 (Folder 6)
  - Pathfinder Press Editorial Committee minutes, 1971-1974 (Folder 7)
  - Printed matter. Clippings and articles about the Socialist Workers Party, 1944-1978 (Folder 8)
  - Publications file. Miscellaneous financial records and memoranda re Socialist Workers Party publications, 1954-1977 (Folder 9)
  - Relations with other American organizations
    - American Socialist Union. Speech by Harry Braverman, 1954 (Folder 10)
    - Black Panther Party. Report by Pearl Chertov, 1969 (Folder 11)
    - Class Struggle League. Serial issue, 1973 (Folder 12)
    - Committee for a Revolutionary Socialist Party. Serial issue and printed article, 1977 (Folder 13)
    - Communist Party. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, discussion documents, pamphlet, and serial issues, 1939-1974. Includes letters by Richard Fraser, Milton Genecin, Clara Kaye, George Novack, and Morris Stein; writings by Genecin, Bill Cumming, Dorothy Healey, and Sam Marcy; and critiques of Trotskyism by the Communist Party and a splinter group, the Communist League (Folder 14)
    - National Caucus of Labor Committees/U.S. Labor Party. Correspondence, discussion document, pamphlet, leaflet, serial issues, and clipping, 1970-1977. Includes letter and writing by Lyndon LaRouche, and publications of the organization (Folder 15)
    - Progressive Labor Party. Report, 1965 (Folder 16)
    - Revolutionary Workers' League. Pamphlets and serial issues published by the League, 1936-1945 (Folder 17)
    - Socialist Labor Party. Correspondence, serial issue, and printed article, 1952-1962. Includes letter by Farrell Dobbs, and publications of the Socialist Labor Party (Folder 18)
    - Spartacist League. Letter, theses, serial issue, and leaflet, 1966-1976. Includes issuances of the Spartacist League, and of Vanguard Newsletter splinter group (Folder 19)
    - Workers League. See also FOURTH INTERNATIONAL FILE/ Great Britain/Socialist Labour League/Workers Revolutionary Party subject file/Accusation campaign
      - General. Correspondence, appeal, and internal documents of the Workers League, 1965-1977. Includes letters by Farrell Dobbs, David North, and Tim Wohlforth (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Frantz, Bob, "From Ultraleftism to Trotskyism," 1972 (Folder 2)
      - Workers League leaflets, 1966-1978 (Folder 3)
      - Workers League pamphlets, 1971-1976 (Folder 4)
    - Workers Party/Independent Socialist League
      - 1945-1946. Correspondence, resolutions, statements, speech, other internal documents, and printed article. Includes letters by James P. Cannon, Felix Morrow, and Max Shachtman; and writings by Cannon, Morrow, Shachtman, and Albert Goldman (Folder 5)
      - 1951-1959. Serial issues published by Independent Socialist League, and report (Folder 6)
  - Subject file
    - Black, Thomas. Printed Congressional hearing testimony by Black, and memorandum by George Breitman, 1956-1976 (Folder 7)
    - Caldwell, Sylvia. Correspondence, memorandum, and Control Commission reports, 1947-1977. Includes letters by Jack Barnes and Farrell Dobbs (Folder 8)
    - Cannon, James P. Biographical data, study guide on writings, memoranda on publications and archives, and miscellany, 1929-1974 (Folder 9)
    - Gelfand, Alan. Correspondence, speech, Political Committee minutes, and legal brief, 1977-1979. Includes letters by Gelfand, Pearl Chertov, and Larry Seigle; speech and legal brief by Gelfand; and disciplinary charge by Jack Barnes (Folder 10)
    - Mangan, Sherry. Correspondence, printed articles, and notes on archival sources, 1962-1978. Includes articles by Alan Wald (Folder 11)
    - Solow, Herbert. Printed article by Alan Wald, 1977 (Folder 12)
  - Writings
    - Cannon, James P., 1929-1954 (Folder 13)
    - Novack, George, 1957-1965 (Folder 14)
    - Preis, Art, 1950 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Swabeck, Arne, 1954 (Folder 2)
    - Wohlforth, Tim, 1957-ca. 1977 (Folder 3)
    - Wright, John G., ca. 1941-ca. 1954 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-1971 (Folder 5)
  - Young Socialist Alliance file. Correspondence, memorandum, report, resolution, discussion documents, and leaflets, 1958-1969. Includes letters by Carl Feingold, George Novack, James Robertson, Ed Shaw, and Tim Wohlforth (Folder 6)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1887-1978
  - Algeria. Pamphlet, leaflets, and photocopy of letter by Ahmed Ben Bella, 1957-1967 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Alliance for Progress. Printed articles and clippings, 1960-1962 (Folder 8)
  - Argentina. Printed articles and clippings, 1961-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Belgium. Serial issue and leaflet, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - Bolivia. Newsletter, printed articles, and clippings
    - 1943-1952 (Folder 11)
    - 1961-1969 (Folder 12)
  - Brazil. Pamphlets, serial issues, printed articles, clippings and leaflets, 1957-1964. Includes issuances of Partido Socialista Brasileiro (Folder 13)
  - Cameroon. Newsletters, 1965 (Folder 14)
  - Canada. Issuances of Canadian Commonwealth Federation, 1953-1955 (Folder 15)
  - China. Serial issue, printed articles, and clippings, 1957-1971 (Folder 16)
  - Colombia. Clippings and miscellany, 1961-1977 (Folder 17)
  - Communist International. Mimeograph and printed copies of documents of first four World Congresses, 1919-1922 (Folder 18)
  - Conferencia Latinoamericana por la Soberania Nacional, la Emancipacion Economica y la Paz (1961: Mexico City)
    - Proceedings, 1961. Bulletins, speeches, reports, resolutions, and declarations (Box 99, Folder 1-2)
    - Press coverage, 1961
      - General. Serial issues, printed articles, and clippings (Folder 3)
      - Avante issues (Folder 4)
    - Miscellany, 1961. Leaflets and bulletins submitted to or handed out at conference, Congressional hearing transcripts, and miscellany (Folder 5)
  - Cuba
    - General. Printed articles, Congressional hearing transcripts, International Confederation of Free Trade Unions statements, translations of Cuban legislation and of writing by Ernesto Guevara, and typescript series of articles by unidentified Cuban, 1959-1965 (Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1960-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Cyprus. Bulletin, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Czechoslovakia. Newsletter, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Deutscher, Isaac
    - General. Memorandum by Tamara Deutscher, and typed and mimeograph transcripts of speeches by Isaac Deutscher, 1967-1968 (Folder 10)
    - Printed matter. Printed articles and clippings, 1955-1968. Includes articles by Isaac Deutscher. See also LEON TROTSKY FILE/Subject file/General/ Printed matter (Folder 11)
  - Devaluation of currency--Great Britain. Clippings, 1967 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Dialectical materialism. Printed study guide, 1951 (Folder 2)
  - Eastman, Max. Printed articles and clipping, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Economics. Pamphlets, printed articles, clippings, and other printed matter, 1944-1970 (Folder 4)
  - Ecuador. Printed articles and clippings, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - El Salvador. Clippings, and Frente Farabundo Marti para la Liberacion Nacional bulletin, 1961-1975 (Folder 6)
  - Ethiopia. Issuances of Ethiopian People's Movement Council, 1965-1966 (Folder 7)
  - Europe, Eastern. Clippings, and Congressional hearing transcripts, 1948-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Fascism--United States. Includes material on fascist and other right-wing movements and politicians in the United States
    - General. Serial issues, printed articles, and clippings
      - 1939 (Folder 9)
      - 1940-1951 (Folder 10)
      - 1960-1978 (Folder 11)
    - Right-wing issuances. Pamphlets, bulletins, and newsletters, many of them issued by Gerald L. K. Smith, 1946-1961 (Folder 12)
  - France. Pamphlets, serial issues, printed articles, and clippings, 1939-1968 (Folder 13)
  - Freud, Sigmund. Printed articles and clippings, 1939-1971 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Gilly, Adolfo. Mimeograph letters and printed article, 1966-1978 (Folder 2)